# Akib Rahman

571-383-6622 | amoha031@odu.edu | linkedin.com/in/akibmr | github.com/akibrhast

### Summary

Full stack software engineer with 4 years of experience using React, Express, Flask, AWS and PostgreSQL/MongoDB to craft creative solutions. I am currently looking for an opportunity where I can apply my skills and knowledge to develop, maintain and manage your enterprise systems.

### EXPERIENCE

#### Software Developer/Architect

Jun 2020 - Present

Open-Lib

Richmond, VA

- Developed a full-stack web application with Flask serving a REST API. With plans to port the Front-End to React
- Implemented Authentication using Flask-Login. Implemented pdf reading capabilities using pdf-js
- Kept track and visualized page numbers and books that are currently being read by a use

#### Software Engineer

Jan 2019 – December 2019

Tahzoo

Richmond, VA

- Built an Azure ECL module for Tridion Sites 9 which allowed clients fine tuned controls of their media data stored in Azure using the Tridion CMS.
- Migrated Tahzoo.com from WordPress to Tridion CMS.
- Developed the DXA application to serve CMS content and implemented elastic search.

#### Information Technology Support Specialist

Feb. 2018 – December 2018

Virginia Commonwealth University

Richmond, VA

- Communicate with managers to set up campus computers used on campus.
- Assess and troubleshoot computer problems brought by students, faculty and staff.
- Maintain upkeep of computers, classroom equipment, and 200 printers across campus.

#### **Internet of Things Research Assistant**

May 2019 – July 2019

Virginia Commonwealth University

Richmond, VA

- $\bullet$  Explored methods to control and measure individual circuit end points in a house using esp32's.
- Developed a central control unit on a raspberry pi to where the esp32 can send data.
- Created a proof of model concept using a giant doll house, esp32s and raspberry-pi and received further funding's.

## Projects

Open-Lib | Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, Docker, Aws

June 2020 - Present

- Developed a full-stack web application with Flask serving a REST API. With plans to port the Front-End to React
- Implemented Authentication using Flask-Login. Implemented pdf reading capabilities using pdf-js
- Kept track and visualized page numbers and books that are currently being read by a user

**Autonomous ARM vehicle** | Arm-Cortex 4 Discovery Board, Assembly, C/C++

May 2018 – May 2020

- Built an autonomous vehicle that can avoid obstacles and navigate a maze.
- Received 2nd place certificate in a class of 50 student in navigating the maze and following the lined track in the fastest possible time.

#### Spyware with OpenCV | OpenCV, Tkinter, keyboard

May 2018 – May 2020

- Built a desktop application using Tkinter and OpenCV
- Application start's on boot, logs all keystroke, records audio-video at intervals, and log the data to an email server.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C/C++/C-Sharp, SQL (Postgres), JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Flask, WordPress, Material-UI, FastAPI

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, IntelliJ, Eclipse

Libraries: pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, OpenCV

#### **EDUCATION**

Springboard San Francisco, CA